{
    "id": "04dcca0a70934c83b6ec7c33af7d9be9",
    "title": "Subject-Verb Agreement",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "The long and the short of the matter ………………………….. that we have been betrayed.",
            "description": "The verb must be singular when two or more subjects together express one idea.",
            "answers": [
                "is",
                "are"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "The chairman and the secretary …………………………………. present.",
            "description": "The verb must be plural when two or more singular subjects are connected by and.",
            "answers": [
                "was",
                "were"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "No nook or corner ……………………………… left unexplored.",
            "description": "The verb must be singular when two or more singular subjects are connected by or.",
            "answers": [
                "was",
                "were"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "Neither Sam nor his brother …………………………….. present there.",
            "description": "The verb must be singular when two or more singular subjects are connected by neither/nor.",
            "answers": [
                "was",
                "were"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "Does anyone …………………………… where Celia lives?",
            "description": "The infinitive does not take the marker –s after do, does or did.",
            "answers": [
                "know",
                "knows"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "……………………………… she in love with somebody else?",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "Is",
                "Are",
                "Does"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "He and I ……………………………. birds of the same feather.",
            "description": "When two singular subjects are connected by and, the verb must be singular.",
            "answers": [
                "is",
                "am",
                "are"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "Everybody …………………………….. frustrated by the delay.",
            "description": "We use a singular verb after everybody.",
            "answers": [
                "was",
                "were"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "Tell the children to raise their …………………………….",
            "description": "We usually use a plural noun after a plural possessive. ",
            "answers": [
                "hand",
                "hands"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "Many people lost their …………………………… in the accident.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "lives",
                "life"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "Neither the minister nor his secretary ………………………………. able to give a satisfactory explanation.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "was",
                "were"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "A good knowledge of at least three languages …………………………… essential for this job.",
            "description": "Here the actual subject is the singular noun knowledge. ",
            "answers": [
                "is",
                "are"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        }
    ]
}